geonet.org.nz 2019-12-15

# Privacy Policy / Contact Us / Home - GNS Science

The Institute of Geological and Nuclear Sciences Limited (GNS Science) complies with the New Zealand Privacy Act 1993 (the Act) when dealing with personal information.

This policy sets out how we will collect, use, disclose and protect your personal information.  We may change this policy at any time.  The change will apply from the date we upload the revised policy.

If you provide personal information to us through this website we will use your personal information:

  * to administer and/or improve our website
  * to provide you with services and products
  * to improve our services
  * to bill you and collect money that you owe us, including authorising and processing credit card transactions
  * to undertake credit checks (where necessary)
  * to investigate and respond to communications from you, including a complaint
  * to apply for employment with us
  * to undertake research or statistical analysis (on an anonymised basis)
  * to protect and/or enforce our legal rights and interests, including defending any claim
  * for any other purpose authorised by you

We may disclose your personal information to:

  * any subsidiary of GNS Science
  * any third party to achieve any of the purposes listed above
  * any business that supports our services and products, including any person that hosts or maintains any underlying IT system or data centre that we use to provide the website or other services and products
  * any other person authorised by you
  * comply with New Zealand law

A business that supports our services and products may be located outside of New Zealand.  This may mean your personal information is held and processed outside New Zealand.

 **Data collection and cookies**

As you interact with our digital channels, we may use automatic data collection technologies, such as cookies, to collect certain information about your equipment, browsing actions, and patterns. We may also use an analytics services such as Google Analytics to assist us with understanding what content people use our website.

We may use Google Analytics on our websites to collect information using cookies or other mechanisms to track your activity. We may collect your IP Address, web browser, location, pages viewed, time spent on site and the number of times you visit.

Cookies are small text files that are stored on a user's device that can collect information about how you browse the website. Cookies may give us information on your location, IP address, browser and platform. If you do not want us to collect this information you can turn off cookies in your browser and deleting them from our device.

This information may be used by us or on behalf of us, to analyse and track data, determine the popularity of certain content, and better understand online activity.

 **Security**

To ensure compliance with legal requirements, such as “Security in the Government Sector (SIGS), the “NZ Information Security Manual” (NZISM) and ISO 27001, to maintain cyber security standards and to ensure the robust delivery of GNS Science IT services, our systems are subject to ongoing monitoring, including activity logging and analysis, as well as occasional formal audit.  The ongoing monitoring of GNS Science IT systems can occur through services provided by one or more specialist third parties.  Such third parties can access information processed by and stored on GNS Science systems.

Subject to certain exceptions under the Act, you have the right to access your readily retrievable personal information and request correction of your personal information.  You may access and request correction of that information by contacting GNS Science.

If you follow a link from our website to any other website, including any social networking site, that site will have its own privacy policy.  You should review that site’s privacy policy before providing any personal information.
